{
    "Personalities": [
      {
            "question": "Who was the 1st Prime Minister of India?",
            "ans": "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "1": "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "2": "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
            "3": "Gulzar Lal Nanda",
            "4": "None of the Above"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first Women External Affair Minister of India was:",
            "ans": "Indira Gandhi",
            "1": "Sushma Swaraj",
            "2": "Jayalalitha",
            "3": "Pratibha Patil",
            "4": "Indira Gandhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following known as Pocket Hercules?",
            "ans": "Manohar Aich",
            "1": "Mike Tyson",
            "2": "Manohar Aich",
            "3": "Manotosh Roy",
            "4": "Muhammad Ali"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following known as Pocket Hercules?",
            "ans": "Manohar Aich",
            "1": "Mike Tyson",
            "2": "Manohar Aich",
            "3": "Manotosh Roy",
            "4": "Muhammad Ali"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was known as Iron man of India?",
            "ans": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "1": "Govind Ballabh Pant",
            "2": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "3": "Subhash Chandra Bose",
            "4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Indian to beat the computers in mathematical wizardry is",
            "ans": "Shakunthala Devi",
            "1": "Ramanujam",
            "2": "Rina Panigrahi",
            "3": "Raja Ramanna",
            "4": "Shakunthala Devi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Jude Felix is a famous Indian player in which of the fields?",
            "ans": "Hockey",
            "1": "Volleyball",
            "2": "Tennis",
            "3": "Football",
            "4": "Hockey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Professor Amartya Sen is famous in which of the fields?",
            "ans": "Economics",
            "1": "Electronics",
            "2": "Economics",
            "3": "Geology",
            "4": "Biochemistry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was Satyajit Ray associated with?",
            "ans": "Film Direction",
            "1": "Classical music",
            "2": "Commercial art",
            "3": "Film Direction",
            "4": "Classical dance"
        },

        {
            "question": "Amjad Ali Khan is associated with which of the following musical instruments?",
            "ans": "Sarod",
            "1": "Veena",
            "2": "Violin",
            "3": "Sitar",
            "4": "Sarod"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is known as the 'Lady with the Lamp'?",
            "ans": "Florence Nightingale",
            "1": "Sarojini Naidu",
            "2": "Indira Gandhi",
            "3": "Film Direction",
            "4": "Joan of Arc"
        },
    ]
}
